<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JFrog DevOps Modernization Workshop on JFrog Workshop</title>
    <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JFrog DevOps Modernization Workshop on JFrog Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Delivery</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/1_continuous_integration_and_delivery.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/1_continuous_integration_and_delivery.html</guid>
      <description>Continuous integration and delivery (CI/CD) is the process for which your software components are built from code, integrated, tested, released, deployed and ultimately delivered to end-users. CI/CD pipelines are the software assembly line that orchestrates the building of your software. This CI/CD pipeline line requires infrastructure. Cloud computing has allowed this infrastructure to become dynamic and ephemeral. On cloud infrastructure, your CI/CD pipelines scale up and down to meet your software delivery demands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an AWS account</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/self_paced/account.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/self_paced/account.html</guid>
      <description>Your account must have the ability to create new IAM roles and scope other IAM permissions.
  If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have an AWS account with Administrator access: create one now by clicking here
 Once you have an AWS account, ensure you are following the remaining workshop steps as an IAM user with administrator access to the AWS account: Create a new IAM user to use for the workshop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fork the Lab Repository</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/1_fork_lab_repo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/1_fork_lab_repo.html</guid>
      <description>To get started, you will need to fork this workshop repository. It contains the files, scripts and configurations that are required to complete the hands-on lab.
 Navigate to https://github.com/jefferyfry/awsworkshop. In the top-right corner of the GitHub repository page, click Fork. Wait for GitHub to complete the forking process. In your Cloud9 terminal, clone the new fork to your local git directory.
$ git clone https://github.com/[username]/awsworkshop.git  In the next sections, you will make changes to your new repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start the Workshop...</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/start_workshop.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/start_workshop.html</guid>
      <description> Getting Started To start the workshop, follow one of the following depending on whether you are&amp;hellip;
 &amp;hellip;running the workshop on your own, or &amp;hellip;attending an AWS hosted event  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Repository Management</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/10_binary_repository_management.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/10_binary_repository_management.html</guid>
      <description>A Binary Repository Manager is a software hub that simplifies the development process for different teams across an organization by helping them to collaborate on building coherent and compatible software components. It does this by centralizing the management of all the binary artifacts generated and used by the organization, thereby overcoming the incredible complexity arising from diverse binary artifact types, their position in the overall workflow and the set of dependencies between them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud9</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/10_cloud9.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/10_cloud9.html</guid>
      <description>AWS Cloud9 is a cloud-based integrated development environment (IDE) that lets you write, run, and debug your code with just a browser. It includes a code editor, debugger, and terminal. Cloud9 comes prepackaged with essential tools for popular programming languages, including JavaScript, Python, PHP, and more, so you don’t need to install files or configure your development machine to start new projects.
Add a new Cloud9 IDE environment 1 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the GitHub Integration</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/10_configure_github_integration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/10_configure_github_integration.html</guid>
      <description>In order for JFrog Pipelines to get access to the code in your awsworkshop repository, we must first set up a Pipelines GitHub integration. This allows Pipelines to authenticate and get access to your GitHub repositories. To do this, we create a GitHub Personal Access Token with the correct permissions.
JFrog Pipelines can also integrate with other source code repositories such as GitHub Enterprise, BitBucket and GitLab.   Go to your GitHub Personal Access Tokens settings page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the Artifactory Integration</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/20_configure_artifactory_integration.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/20_configure_artifactory_integration.html</guid>
      <description>Similar to the GitHub Integration, in the following steps you will configure an Artifactory Integration that allows JFrog Pipelines to also access your Artifactory repositories in order to publish your artifacts and build info. You will do this by creating an API key.
Artifactory offers a universal solution supporting all major package formats including Alpine, Maven, Gradle, Docker, Conda, Conan, Debian, Go, Helm, Vagrant, YUM, P2, Ivy, NuGet, PHP, NPM, RubyGems, PyPI, Bower, CocoaPods, GitLFS, Opkg, SBT and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevSecOps</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/20_dev_sec_ops.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/10_devops_cloud/20_dev_sec_ops.html</guid>
      <description>Any security issue identified by a security scanning tool needs to be reviewed by a very small security team that may even lack the technical knowledge. This challenge can be reduced by shifting left to the developer and operations teams, making them also responsible for security and compliance, and moving security earlier in the software delivery process. Source code, dependency and artifact security scanning are some examples of moving security into the development process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the Initialization Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/30_configure_initialization_pipeline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/30_configure_initialization_pipeline.html</guid>
      <description>Next, we will update the lab pipelines to add your new GitHub and Artifactory integrations. In previous steps, you [forked and cloned the lab repository.]() We will modify the initialization pipeline in your forked Hoare repository to add these integrations.
 In your local git directory, open awsworkshop/jfrog_pipelines/init-jfrog.yml in an editor. Update the resources section of the file to use your new forked repository. Change the path to use your username.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create an IAM role for your workspace</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/30_iamrole.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/30_iamrole.html</guid>
      <description>Starting from here, when you see command to be entered such as below, you will enter these commands into Cloud9 IDE. You can use the Copy to clipboard feature (right hand upper corner) to simply copy and paste into Cloud9. In order to paste, you can use Ctrl + V for Windows or Command + V for Mac.
  Follow this deep link to create an IAM role with Administrator access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attach the IAM role to your Workspace</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/40_workspaceiam.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/40_workspaceiam.html</guid>
      <description> Follow this deep link to find your Cloud9 EC2 instance Select the instance, then choose Actions / Instance Settings / Attach/Replace IAM Role  Choose Jfrog-Workshop-Admin from the IAM Role drop down, and select Apply   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure the Pipeline Source</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/40_configure_pipeline_source.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/40_configure_pipeline_source.html</guid>
      <description>In these next steps, we will add the build pipelines as a JFrog Pipelines source. This will allow JFrog Pipelines to execute these pipelines automatically whenever there is a commit or manually as needed.
A Pipeline Source represents a source control repository (such as GitHub or BitBucket) where Pipelines definition files can be found. A pipeline source connects to the repository through an integration.   In your JFrog Platform instance, go to Pipelines ► Pipeline Sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update IAM settings for your Workspace</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/45_cloud.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/45_cloud.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud9 normally manages IAM credentials dynamically. This isn&amp;rsquo;t currently compatible with the EKS IAM authentication, so we will disable it and rely on the IAM role instead.
  Return to your workspace and click the gear icon (in top right corner), or click to open a new tab and choose &amp;ldquo;Open Preferences&amp;rdquo; Select AWS SETTINGS Turn off AWS managed temporary credentials Close the Preferences tab   Let&amp;rsquo;s run the command below, the following actions will take place as we do that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute the Initialization Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/50_execute_initialization_pipeline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/50_execute_initialization_pipeline.html</guid>
      <description>The first pipeline that we will execute will initialize our environment. This pipeline will create users, groups, permissions, repositories, Xray policies and watches, Xray indexes and access federation. This prepares our JFrog Platform instance to run our gradle and npm build pipelines.
This pipeline initializes the JFrog Platform for the next build pipelines by creating the necessary users, repositories, permissions and Xray configuration. It does this by using the JFrog Platform REST APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get a Free JFrog Platform Instance</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/55_jfrog_free.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/55_workshop_setup/55_jfrog_free.html</guid>
      <description>Use the JFrog Platform Cloud Free Tier to get your own JFrog Platform instance with Artifactory, Xray and Pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Execute the NPM Build Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/70_execute_npm_build_pipeline.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/70_execute_npm_build_pipeline.html</guid>
      <description>The npm_build pipeline builds our web application. This pipeline uses a NpmBuild native Pipelines step build the user interface components. Next, it uses NpmPublish to publish the components. DockerBuild and DockerPush native steps are used to build a Docker image and push it to Artifactory. It then scans the build using the XrayScan native step. Then it pushes the produced artifacts to the &amp;ldquo;staging&amp;rdquo; repository in Artifactory along with all build information by using the PromoteBuild native step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure ECS Permissions</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/80_configure_ecs_permissions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/80_configure_ecs_permissions.html</guid>
      <description>In the previous section, we set up JFrog Pipelines to authenticate and publish images to Artifactory. In this section, we will add the same credentials to AWS Secrets Manager and create an ECS IAM role. This will allow Amazon ECS to pull the image from Artifactory and deploy it.
Private registry authentication for ECS tasks using AWS Secrets Manager enables you to store your credentials securely and then reference them in your container definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy Your Image with ECS</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/90_deploy_your_image.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/90_deploy_your_image.html</guid>
      <description>We are now ready to deploy your image with Amazon ECS.
Private registry authentication for ECS tasks using AWS Secrets Manager enables you to store your credentials securely and then reference them in your container definition. This allows your ECS tasks to use images from private repositories.   Go to the Amazon ECS console first-run wizard. In the Container definition section, click configure on the custom option. For the container name, specify npm-app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/100_conclusion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jefferyfry.github.io/awsworkshop/70_hands-on_lab/100_conclusion.html</guid>
      <description>In this workshop, we demonstrated using the JFrog Platform to create CI/CD pipelines to build an application, manage the artifacts, scan the artifacts for security vulnerabilities and license compliance, and publish the artifacts to a staging repository. Now you have some basic understanding of the JFrog Platform, we encourage you to use it with your existing build tools, like Maven, Gradle, Ivy and Ant and work with packaging systems of other development platforms, like NuGet, RubyGems or NPM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
